Gaurav Mishra

Salesforce Developer

Salesforce Developer with 3.6+ years of experience designing, developing, and implementing custom applications to enhance business processes and drive user adoption. Proven ability to collaborate effectively with cross-functional teams to deliver solutions that meet specific business needs. Skilled in Apex, Visualforce, Lightning Web Components(LWC), SOQL, and Salesforce APIs. Eager to contribute expertise to a fast-paced and innovative environment.





http://linkedin.com/in/ekgrvo

9453917397

Gurugram, Hariyana, India



Salesforce Knowledge

- Has more than 3.6 year+ of experience in Application Software Designing, Development, Testing and Implementation. Have good experience with Salesforce Customization, Security Access, creating profiles, roles, users, page layouts.
- Strong Implementation experience using Custom objects, Triggers, workflows/ workflow rules, approval.
- Experience in development, administration, configuration, Implementation, and Support of sales

force CRM, and Salesforce applications based on **Apex Language** and leveraging **Force.com** Platform.

 using Sales force Administration (SFA), Profiles, Creating Roles, Page Layouts, Org-Wide default, Sharing rules, WorkFlows, Approval Workflow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Matrix Solution - Dec -2023 - 02- Aug -2024 Salesforce Developer :

- Developed and built solutions on force.com platform using OOB features, Visualforce, LWC, Apex, Web Services and API's.
- $\bullet\,$ Developed custom applications on Sales Cloud and Service Cloud using Apex, Visualforce, and

Lightning Web Components

- Designed and developed Salesforce Sales Cloud solutions using SOQL, significantly increasing sales by
- Implemented robust SOAP Web Services, improving integration with external systems by 40%
- Innovated an approach to integrate Salesforce with disparate data repositories, unifying customer profiles and boosting engagement strategies by 40%
- Applied programming knowledge to data management, scripting languages, API, and integration tasks.
- Integrated Salesforce with external systems using REST and SOAP APIs, ensuring data consistency, security, and a seamless user experience.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Introduction to Salesforce products: Sales Cloud, Service Cloud and Marketing Cloud.

Data modeling in Salesforce: Custom objects, fields, and relationships.

Data import/export techniques using Data Loader and other tools

Data security and sharing settings.

Experienced in declarative tool development in salesforce

Hands on Experience in Apex, Apex trigger, Asynchronous Apex and Apex testing.

Experience in Building user interfaces with Visualforce pages.

Knowledge about Lightning Component Framework and building Lightning web components.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Salesforce:

• Apex, Triggers, SOQL & SOSL, Lightning Web Component, Salesforce lightning, XML, VisualForce, Workflow, APIs (REST,SOAP), Service cloud, Sales cloud.

Ncino:

• Routes, Screens, Change Memo, Loan, Translation Record, Product Package, Document Manager, Covenants.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology (B.Tech) 2016 - 2020 Dr.A.P.J.Abdul Kalam Technical University

Computer Science Engineering.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IGT Solutions Pvt Ltd - June-2022 – Nov 2023 Salesforce Developer :

- Streamlined the Salesforce.com platform by utilizing complex Apex Programming to reduce workflow process time by 35%
- Implemented Visualforce Pages and Lightning components, improving user interface and user experience for over 5000 users
- Developed custom applications on Sales Cloud and Service Cloud using Apex, Visualforce, and

Lightning Web Components

- Introduced Salesforce.com Development and Administration procedures, increasing system efficiency
- Increased sedata accuracy by 30% by leveraging Apex Data Loader for bulk import and export of data

Successfully led a team of 5 in Salesforce.com Implementation, contributing to seamless transition of

client's CRM to Salesforce.com

- Designed and developed Salesforce Sales Cloud solutions using SOQL, significantly increasing sales by 25%
- Implemented robust SOAP Web Services, improving integration with external systems by 50%

WORK EXPERIENCE

WIPRO – January -2021 – June 2022 Junior Salesforce Developer

- Deployed Apex triggers that automatically updated RW's Salesforce records with data from external systems, reducing manual data entry time by 90%.
- Developed a custom application using the Force.com platform which boosted the sales efficiency of 5 businesses by 31%.
- Reduced the time it took to enter data into the system by 85% developing an integration between Microsoft Excel and Salesforce.
- Created custom user-interfaces by building VisualForce pages in Lightning which improved user experience by 85% and streamlined workflow processes.
- Applied programming knowledge to data management, scripting languages, API, and integration tasks.

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

HINDI

